Phillip Rees

UI Designer & Front-End Developer

I've worked with local, government, and international clients developing solutions with code, pixels, and ink.

I get inspired by new ideas and I love discovering age-old strategies and wisdom. I know the value of designing for inclusivity right from the get-go, and I take our user's needs seriously.

I never shy away from trying something different if it brings our team and the business real value. I see constraints as an opportunity for innovative ideas to flourish, and I love finding simple solutions to complex problems.

I want to work for a forward-thinking company that tries to make a difference, and knows that delivering an awesome customer experience is essential for good business.

In my spare time I skate, cycle, and run. I like to go to concerts and gigs, and I get motivated by hard-hitting music of any genre. I try to stay on top of my health and fitness, and I enjoy thinking about the future.

Career Summary

In my previous role at CDSM, I worked to tight deadlines for demanding clients like Hwb, Mitsubishi, and Boots to create bespoke, professional E-Learning experiences and admin dashboards. I was hired as a Graphic Designer, became an E-Learning UI designer, and worked my way up to Front-End Developer.

I'm now at Cruise Nation, where I work closely with management, marketing, and product teams to design, implement, and regularly ship web features, optimisations, and UI improvements to thousands of visitors every month across a wide range of browsers and devices as part of an award-winning digital team.

- 5 years Industry Graphic & UI Design experience
- 3 years Professional Front-End Development experience

Key Knowledge Areas

- JavaScript ES6+ & JS Frameworks
- Cross-Browser Development & Responsive Design
- Web Performance Optimisation
- Node.js & Continuous Integration
- Front-End Debugging & JavaScript Unit Testing
- SEO, Analytics, and A/B Testing
- Presenting, Pitching, & Product Ownership
- Visual Design & Corporate Branding
- User Experience Design Patterns
- Accessibility & Inclusive Design
- Print & Mixed Media Design

Work Experience – Cruise Nation

Front-End Developer (July 2018 – Present)

As part of Cruise Nation's highly mobile digital marketing team, I work close to the metal on our online strategy, helping to guide decision making, project planning, user experience, and brand strategy. Being a small team, we need to produce reliable code quickly and test creative ideas on a dime.

My main role is to action requests from the marketing team, often starting from scratch from a short brief, then creating front-end components in JavaScript, CSS, and HTML. I provide technical assistance in the form of bug fixes or utilities, and also maintain our developer tools, ensuring our developer experience is frictionless. For us, every commit is a deployment, which allows us to rapidly stage, share previews, and refine our code before we go live.

I also maintain our Jest powered test suites, front-end QA & integration tests, and ensure code style and documentation are kept up to date. When I can, I also write the odd script to automate tasks to free up the team to work on more important things.

Skills Developed: JavaScript ES6, Web Application Architecture, Event-Driven Development, React, JSX, Pug, CSS3+, NodeJS, Automated Testing, JSON Schema, NodeJS, Bash Shell Scripting, Unit Testing, Modern Browser APIs, API Design, Regex, Type Systems, Dev Experience, Web Microdata, Web Performance, WordPress Development, SEO, Copywriting, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

Work Experience – CDSM Interactive Solutions Ltd.

Front-End Developer (April 2017 – July 2018)

After proving myself as a competent designer, I was given the chance to improve my frontend development skills working on CDSM's corporate platform Thinqi, where I was introduced to modern JavaScript application architecture, design patterns, agile methodology, unit testing, and much more. I was tasked with building teacher and administrator facing dashboards to allow our users to self-service features, get stats about their students, or create and host events.

Skills Developed: UX Research, UI Development, MVC / OOP Patterns, Git, Markdown, CSS3/SCSS, CoffeeScript, Backbone, HTML5, Accessibility / WCAG, GDPR Guidelines, Cross-Browser testing

Graphic & UI Designer (August 2015 – April 2017)

Beginning as a graphic designer using photoshop to manipulate photos from photoshoots, my workload constantly evolved in this role. I took the time to learn new technologies and helped the team become familiar with new tools like Articulate Storyline, culminating in some of our most polished, bespoke digital learning that was recognised as industry leading by Mitsubishi HQ. I became responsible for producing, optimising, and maintaining the UI and Interactive content of our bespoke e-learning modules using Storyline going forward.

Skills Developed: UX Research, UI Development, Photomanipulation, Vector Graphic Design, Digital Animation, Articulate Storyline 2/360

Work Experience – Freelance & Hobbyist

Graphic Designer & Web Developer (September 2013 – September 2015)

My hobbyist role as a web developer and interest in UI design distilled into a professional career after I left university to freelance. I helped small business clients to create easy to manage websites using WordPress and got to flex both my design and development skills creating custom themes to their specifications, interacting with and presenting data, and working with Front-End frameworks and libraries.

Skills Developed: WooCommerce Development, WordPress Theme Development, Sage Roots, UI Development, Print Design, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, SEO, Timekeeping, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Education

Devon Co (2020+)

3D for Designers

Udemy (2016+)

Facebook Clone with Laravel, TDD, Vue.js & Tailwind CSS JavaScript Design Patterns JavaScript Unit Testing with Mocha, Chai, and Sinon Advanced CSS and Sass

Pluralsight Code Schools (2016)

CSS Cross Country

JavaScript Road Trip

University of Wales Trinity Saint David (2015 – 2016)

BA Advertising & Brand Design Winter 2015/Spring 2016 Term

BA Graphic Design Autumn 2015/Winter 2016 Term

LinkedIn Learning / Lynda.com (2014 – 2016)

Laravel 4 Essential Training Photoshop CC Mastery Illustrator CC Mastery

Neath Port-Talbot College (2014)

AS Graphic Communication (B)

CompTIA (2012)

CompTIA A+ (Pass)

CompTIA Network+ (Pass)

Neath Port-Talbot College (2008)

BTEC First Diploma in Media (Pass)

References

Cruise Nation

Jake Macklin Web Developer *linkedin.com/in/jake-macklin-47362543*

CDSM

Rebecca Picton-James Project Manager *linkedin.com/in/rebecca-picton-james-108871125*

Jay PriceSenior UX Designerlinkedin.com/in/jaysamuelpriceRhys WilliamsLead Interactive Designerlinkedin.com/in/rhysowainwilliams

Get in Touch

Thanks for taking the time to find out more about my skills and experiences.

I am always open to hearing about exciting full-time and remote opportunities, so if you'd like to discuss roles, experience, or just have a chat, don't hesitate to contact me. I'm available by phone on weekdays after 6PM, over the weekends, or via e-mail and LinkedIn anytime.

Phone +44 7415 669 579

Email piprees@outlook.com

LinkedIn *linkedin.com/in/piprees*

Behance behance.com/piprees

GitHub *github.com/piprees*

Twitter *twitter.com/piprees*